Alfred H. Barr, Jr. Papers
The Museum of Modern Art, Publisher
- Series 15: Family Letters and Early Education
  - Subseries E: Miscellaneous
    - Handwritten notes on "Dante", Signed by AHB (Box 1, Folder 15.E.2)
    - Photographs, Several of AHB relatives (Box 1, Folder 15.E.3)
- Series 16: Miscellaneous
  1 box of material received too late to be either integrated with other Barr Papers or to be microfilmed; in alphabetical order
  Lists & envelopes from previous attempts to organize Barr Papers in 1st folde r)
  - Artists in Exile, 1942; Catalog & signed George Platt Lynes photo (Box 1, Folder 16.[1])
  - Brancusi, 1939; 2 "caps," signed, with note of explanation from MSB: mementos of a party in Brancusi's studio; Moved to Box 2 & 3 (Box 2, 3, Folder 16.[2])
  - The Chapbook, 1920-1923; 4 issues: June, Mar., Feb. '23; Aug. '20 (Box 1, Folder 16.[3])
  - Arthur Cohen/MSB TLS, 14 May 1977, 22 items Appraisals of ALS with the originals (Box 1, Folder 16.[4])
  - Coggeshall, Susan Wison, Aug. 15 1933; 22 items (Daughter of Seely Perkins) ALS (Box 1, Folder 16.[5])
  - Dali ALS Postcard, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 16.[6])
  - Delaunay, Sonia, 1939; 3 items Apollinaire documents, given by SD. to AHB rec'd into Lib. 1973 (Box 1, Folder 16.[7])
  - ALS: Fini (Box 1, Folder 16.[8])
  - Goetz: Authentication of a van Gogh painting, 1949; See also AHB Pers. Corresp. Series (Box 1, Folder 16.[9])
  - Guggenheim, Peggy, 1942, 1962; 7 items Printed matter (Box 1, Folder 16.[10])
  - Hitccock, Henry Russell, 1927-1928; 1928 Aug 12 ALS 1928 Apr. 18 ALS 1927 Dec. 5; See also Abstract Art, Cubism, Futurism; A.13 (Box 1, Folder 16.[11])
  - Lewis, Wyndham, 1927, 1939, 1941; 3 ALS; 4 TLS; 1 sketch (Box 1, Folder 16.[12])
  - ALS Lipchitz to Barr, 1944 Dec. 27 (Box 1, Folder 16.[13])
  - Martin, Maria ALS (Box 1, Folder 16.[14])
  - Moore, Marianne TLS, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 16.[15])
  - Mop, Maximillian/AHB TLS, 1941; 8 items (Box 1, Folder 16.[16])
  - Re: Museum of Modern Art, 1934; Printed matter (Box 1, Folder 16.[17])
  - 2 ALS Paul J. Sachs to Barr, 1925-1926; 3/14/1926; 11/3/1925 (Box 1, Folder 16.[18])
  - ALS Steiglitz to Barr, Jan. 3 1944 (Box 1, Folder 16.[19])
  - ALS Randall Thompson to Barr, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 16.[20])
  - 2 ALS "Laurence" to "Alf" (Box 1, Folder 16.[21])
  - 1920s general Folder, 1918-1929; 10 items incl. n.d. gallery list for Wellesley students 1929: unfinished poem 1929: ALS Kiesler to Barr, ALS Stefan Hirsch card 1927: 6 ALS to Barr in London 1918: Sonnet by Barr TL (Box 1, Folder 16.[22])
- Series 17: Removed Material; Formerly 3g and 3h
  - Subseries A: Series 1a 3g Material: Recommendations, ca.1930s-1970s
    6"
    - General A - K (Box 1, Folder 17.A.1.a)
    - General L - Z (Box 1, Folder 17.A.1.b)
    - Guggenheim Foundation A - J (Box 1, Folder 17.A.2.a)
    - Guggenheim Foundation K - Y (Box 1, Folder 17.A.2.b)
    - Guggenheim Foundation - Addenda, ca. 1934-1947 (Box 1, Folder 17.A.2.c)
    - Guggenheim Award Jury (Box 1, Folder 17.A.3)
    - "Artists as Lecturers and Teachers", ca. 1940s (Box 1, Folder 17.A.4)
    - Ford Foundation and Fund for the Republic (Box 1, Folder 17.A.5)
    - Trustees, staff, 1947, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 17.A.6)
    - Fogg Fellowship in Modern Art, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 17.A.7)
  - Subseries B: Series 1a 3h Material: Fund Raising, ca.1930s-1970s
    10". Mimeographed Steering Committee Minutes, 1959-1962, removed
    - Mrs. Simon Guggenheim, 1942, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 17.B.1.a)
    - Mrs. Victor Reisenfeld, 1961, 1964, 1965; Incl. AHB eulogy (Box 1, Folder 17.3.B.1b)
    - Rockefeller, John 3rd M/M, ca. 1948-1964 (Box 1, Folder 17.B.1c)
    - Spingold, Nate B., ca. 1960-1965 (Box 1, Folder 17.B.1.d)
    - Smith, Louise, ca. 1953-1964 (Box 1, Folder 17.B.1.e)
    - Stern, Louis E., ca. 1959-1965; Stern, Max, item 1957 (Box 1, Folder 17.B.1.f)
    - Thompson, David G., 1959, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 17.B.1.g)
    - Thirty-fifth and Thirtieth Anniversary Campaigns: Possible Contributions, 1959-1963 (Box 1, Folder 17.B.2.a)
    - Thirty-fifth and Thirtieth Anniversary Campaigns: Given Contributions A - K, 1959-1963 (Box 1, Folder 17.B.2.b.i)
    - Thirty-fifth and Thirtieth Anniversary Campaigns: Given Contributions L - Z, 1959-1963 (Box 1, Folder 17.b.2.b.ii)
    - Thirty-fifth and Thirtieth Anniversary Campaigns: Lists, committees, etc., 1960-1962; Ganz, lists, lists of prospects (Box 1, Folder 17.B.2.c.i)
    - Thirty-fifth and Thirtieth Anniversary Campaigns: Lists, committees, etc., 1959; Lists, suggestions (Box 1, Folder 17.B.2.c.ii)
    - Thirty-fifth and Thirtieth Anniversary Campaigns: Berne Auction, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 17.B.2.d)
    - Thirty-fifth and Thirtieth Anniversary Campaigns: Par-Bernet Thirtieth Anniversary Auction, 1960; 4 folders (Box 1, Folder 17.B.2.e)
    - Thirty-fifth and Thirtieth Anniversary Campaigns: Westbury, Long Island Benefit Exhibition, This unit concerned with the exhibition proper, i.e. not 3h except for fact that exhibition's purpose was fund raising Belongs with Registrar's records (Box 1, Folder 17.B.2.f)
    - MoMA finance and budgetary matters, 1942, 1943; Incl. handwritten AHB letter Salaries discussed Interesting due to date of correspondence (Box 1, Folder 17.B.3)
  - Subseries C: Items removed from Series 10: Personal/Desk, July 23, 1984
    - Letter, June 9, 1971; AHB to JTS Re: Bill Rubin From folder 10.A.69 (Box 1, Folder 17.C.[1])
    - "Lieberman", 1950-1951, 1953; From folder 10.A.41 (Box 1, Folder 17.C.[2])
    - "Saftey" and "Classification of Collections for purposes of protection in case of war", From folders 10.C.1 and 10.C.2 (Box 1, Folder 17.C.[3])
- Series 18: Alfred H. Barr, Jr. / Nelson A. Rockefeller Papers, ca. 1947-1971
  According to guidelines set forth by Clive Phillpot in his memo of 1/26/82 to Richard E. Oldenburg re: RDH Papers, this Group of papers belongs to "Category 2, papers which can be filmed but which should be impounded for an undetermined period of years." Much of this material mentions prices paid for works of art purchased by NAR (i.e., category 2b)
  - Subseries I: NAR Collection: Acqusitions, ca. 1947-1971
    - Subseries A: Correspondence, 1947-1971
      *Misc. refers to letters in which more than one artist is mentioned; correspondence in Misc./General units arranged chronologically.
      - Misc.*/General, ca. 1947-1958; 1070 items(?) (Box 1, Folder 18.I.A.1)
      - Misc./General, 1960-1971; 105 items 3 n.d. (Box 1, Folder 18.I.A.2)
      - A - B, 1947-1969; 115 items (Box 1, Folder 18.I.A.3)
      - C - D (Box 1, Folder 18.I.A.4)
      - E - L (Box 1, Folder 18.I.A.5)
      - M - O (Box 1, Folder 18.I.A.6)
      - P - Z (Box 1, Folder 18.I.A.7)
      - Picasso I, ca. 1948-1956; 225 items (Box 1, Folder 18.I.A.8)
      - Picasso II, 125 items Re: transactions which took place between 1957-1967 (Box 1, Folder 18.I.A.9)
      - Glass sculptures, 1964-1965; ca. 40 items 2 1964 catalogs 1 marked (Box 1, Folder 18.I.A.10)
    - Subseries B: Lists and Clippings, 1955, 1957 1959
      - Correspondence and lengthly lists relevant to Nelson Rockefeller's bequest of works of art to the Museum, 1955, 1957 1959; Barr's choices detailed ca. 105 items (Box 1, Folder 18.I.B.1)
  - Subseries II: NAR Collection: Catalog, ca. 1969-1970
    - Subseries A: Barr "Preface", ca. 1969-1970
      Published as "On Nelson Rockefeller and Modern Art." In: Miller, Dorothy C., ed.The Nelson A. Rockefeller Collection: Masterpieces of Modern Art. NY: Hudson Hills; c. 1981
      - Working notes (Box 1, Folder 18.II.A.1)
      - Typed draft, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 18.II.A.2)
  - Subseries III: Rockefeller window(s)
    - Subseries A: Plans, etc.
      - Plans, etc., 1954-1955, 1961; Plans, photographs, relevant correspondence for various windows to be executed at Pocantico Hills: 1954-55 (Matisse) + 1961 (Manessier, Goodnough, Soulages). ca.35 items. (Box 1, Folder 18.III.A.1)
  - Subseries IV: NAR and New York State Council on the Arts
    - NAR and New York State Council on the Arts, All mimeographed material which can be found elsewhere (Box 1, Folder 18.IV.1)